Register of the Eric Cyril Bellquist Papers, 1928-1979
Hoover Institution Archives
Eric Cyril Bellquist papers
1928-1979
81092
Bellquist, Eric Cyril, 1904-1979
66 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 2 card file boxes, 9 envelopes, 2 phonotape reels, 3 phonorecords, 1 motion picture film reel. (30 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, reports, memoranda, writings, press releases, printed matter, and audiovisual material, relating to American propaganda activities during and after World War II; postwar American foreign policy, especially in Scandinavia; political conditions in the United States, Sweden, and elsewhere in Europe; and public opinion formation.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1981.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
United States. Dept. of State.; United States. Office of War Information.; International cooperation.; Propaganda, American.; Propaganda, Anti-communist.; Public opinion.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Propaganda.; Scandinavia.; Scandinavia--Politics and government.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Foreign relations--20th century.; United States--Politics and government--20th century.; United States--Politics and government.; World War, 1939-1945--United States.; Sweden--Politics and government--1905-; Europe--Politics and government--20th century.; Sweden.; Europe.; Phonotapes.; Phonorecords.; Moving-pictures.
Biographical Note
1904, Sept. 22 Born, Jersey City, New Jersey
1928 M.A., University of California at Berkeley
1932 PhD., University of California at Berkeley
1936-1972 Professor, University of California at Berkeley
1943-1945 Aug. Principal Regional Specialist and Area Chief for Sweden in the Overseas Branch of the Office of War Information
1945 Sept.-Dec. Regional Director for Western Europe, Overseas Branch, Office of War Information and for Interim International Information Division, Department of State
1946 Jan.-Aug. Acting Chief, Area Division I (Europe and the British Commonwealth), Office of International Information and Cutural Affairs
1946 Sept.-Dec. Acting Chairman, Department of Political Science, University of California at Berkeley
1947 Feb.-Aug. Chief, Area Division I (Europe and the British Commonwealth), Office of International Information and Cultural Affairs
1949-1951 Aug. Public Affairs Officer at the American Embassy in Stockholm and Director of the United States Information Service in Sweden
1979 Died
Series Description
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1932-1973 (Box 1)
  Notes, correspondence, and writings arranged by physical form
- OFFICE OF WAR INFORMATION, 1943 MAY-1945 SEPTEMBER 15 (Boxes 1-15)
  Articles, booklets, cables and dispatches, flyers, magazines, memoranda, newsletters, notes, pamphlets, printed matter, reports, and telegrams arranged chronologically by year
- INTERIM INTERNATIONAL INFORMATION DIVISION (IIID), 1945 SEPTEMBER 16-DECEMBER 31 (Boxes 15-16)
  Memoranda, press releases, printed matter, and reports arranged by physical form and subject
- OFFICE OF INTERNATIONAL INFORMATION AND CULTURAL AFFAIRS (OIC), 1946 JANUARY-AUGUST AND 1949 AUGUST (Boxes 16-27)
  Printed matter, telegrams, press releases, memoranda, newsletters, notes, reports, correspondence arranged chronologically by year. Includes some materials between 1946 August and 1949 August relating to the activities of the OIC
- PUBLIC AFFAIRS OFFICER, UNITED STATES DEPARTMENT OF STATE, 1949-1951 AUGUST (Boxes 27-31)
  Printed matter, reports, pamphlets, magazines, telegrams, newsletters arranged alphabetically by subject. Includes some materials from 1951 August to 1953 relating to Bellquist's activities as a Public Affairs Officer
- SUBJECT FILE, 1928-1979 (Boxes 31-66)
  Printed matter, press releases, articles, reports, notes, newsletters, pamphlets, memoranda, cables and dispatches, speeches and statements, and fliers arranged alphabetically by subject
- OVERSIZE MATERIAL, 1944-1945 (Box 67)
  Two scrapbooks, one hand drawn political cartoon, and Office of War Information organizational charts
- INDEX CARD FILE, n.d. (Boxes 68-69)
  Bibliographic files arranged alphabetically by author
- PHONOTAPES, n.d. (Tape cabinet)
- PHONORECORDS, 1945-1970 (Record cabinet)
- MOVING PICTURE, 1951 (Film shelf)
- PHOTOGRAPHS (Photograph file)
Container List
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1932-1973
  - General (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (Folder 2)
  - Notes (Folder 3-4)
  - Writings (Folder 5)
- OFFICE OF WAR INFORMATION OFFICE FILE, 1943 MAY-1945 SEPTEMBER 15
  - General (undated)
    - General (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - American propaganda booklets, pamphlets, magazines, newsletters and flyers arranged by country towards which the propaganda was directed
      - General (Folder 7)
      - Czechoslovakia (Folder 8)
      - Denmark (Folder 9-10)
      - Egypt (Folder 11)
      - France (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Germany (Folder 2)
      - Ireland (Folder 3)
      - Italy (Folder 4)
      - Latin America (Folder 5)
      - Middle East
      - Netherlands. Includes The Flying Dutchman (Folder 7-10)
      - Norway (Folder 11)
      - Norway (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Poland (Folder 2)
      - Portugal (Folder 3)
      - United States (Folder 4-8)
      - United States (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
      - Soviet Union (Folder 3)
      - Spain (Folder 4)
      - Sweden (Folder 5-7)
    - Office files
      - General (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Articles (Folder 2)
      - Cables and dispatches
        - General (Folder 3)
        - Davis, Elmer, Director of the Office of War Information (Folder 4)
        - Denmark (Folder 5)
        - Finland (Folder 6)
        - Sweden (Folder 7)
      - Directives
        - Denmark (Folder 8-9)
        - Finland (Folder 10-11)
        - Norway (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
        - Sweden (Folder 3-5)
      - Notes (Folder 6)
      - Reports (Folder 7)
    - Subject file
      - Finland (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Germany. Includes description of the German propaganda film, Freedom's Paradise (Folder 2)
      - Norway (Folder 3)
      - Sweden (Folder 4)
  - 1942
    - Office files
      - Agendas, memoranda and minutes of intelligence officers' meetings (Folder 5-6)
      - Notes (Folder 7)
    - Subject file
      - American Political Science Association (Folder 8)
      - Commonwealth Club of California (Folder 9)
      - Denmark (Folder 10)
      - Finland (Folder 11)
      - National Broadcasting Corporation - Inter-American University of the Air (Folder 12)
      - Norway (Folder 13)
      - Poland (Folder 14)
      - Sweden (Folder 15)
  - 1943
    - General (Folder 16)
    - Office files
      - General (Folder 17)
      - Articles and other printed matter (Folder 18)
      - Broadcasts (Folder 19)
      - Memoranda (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Minutes. Includes intelligence officers' meetings (Folder 2)
      - Notes (Folder 3)
    - Subject file
      - Denmark
        - General (Folder 4)
        - Royal Danish Legation (Folder 5)
      - Finland
        - General (Folder 6)
        - Articles (Folder 7)
        - Cables and dispatches (Folder 8)
        - Memoranda (Folder 9)
        - Notes (Folder 10)
        - Telegrams (Folder 11)
      - Germany (Folder 12)
      - Iceland (Folder 13)
      - Norway (Folder 14)
      - Sweden
        - General
          - General (Folder 15)
          - American-Scandinavian Foundation (Folder 16)
          - Legation of Sweden (Folder 17)
          - New Sweden Historical Association (Folder 18)
        - Articles and other printed matter (Folder 19)
        - Cables and dispatches
          - General (Folder 20)
          - Swedish Home Service (Folder 21)
          - Swedish Overseas Service (Folder 22)
        - Memoranda (Folder 23)
        - Notes (Folder 24)
        - Reports (Folder 25)
        - Telegrams (Folder 26)
  - 1944
    - General (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Office files
      - General (Folder 2)
      - Memoranda (Folder 3)
      - Notes (Folder 4)
      - Reports (Folder 5)
    - Subject file
      - Belgium (Folder 6)
      - Compulsory military training (Folder 7)
      - Denmark
        - General (Folder 8)
        - Department of State
          - Airgrams (Folder 9)
          - Incoming telegrams (Folder 10)
        - Memoranda (Folder 11)
        - Reports (Folder 12)
      - Finland
        - General (Folder 13)
        - Articles. Includes copies of The White Falcon (Folder 14)
        - Cables and dispatches
          - General (Folder 15)
          - Finnish Home Service (Folder 16)
          - Finnish Overseas Service (Folder 17)
        - Correspondence (Folder 18)
        - Department of State
          - Airgram (Folder 19)
          - Incoming telegrams (Folder 20)
        - Memoranda (Folder 21)
        - Notes (Folder 22)
        - Reports (Folder 23)
        - Telegram (Folder 24)
      - France (Folder 25)
      - Norway
        - Department of State
          - Airgram (Box 10, Folder 1)
          - Incoming telegrams (Folder 2)
          - Press releases (Folder 3)
        - Memoranda (Folder 4)
        - Notes (Folder 5)
        - Reports (Folder 6)
      - President's War Relief Control Board (Folder 7)
      - Scandinavia (Folder 8)
      - Sweden
        - General
          - General (Folder 9)
          - American-Scandinavian Foundation (Folder 10)
          - Department of State - Incoming telegrams (Folder 11)
          - Legation of Sweden (Folder 12)
        - Articles and other printed matter (Folder 13-14)
        - Cables and dispatches
          - General (Folder 15)
          - Swedish Home Service (Folder 16)
          - Swedish Overseas Service (Folder 17)
        - Correspondence (Folder 18)
        - Memoranda (Box 11, Folder 1)
        - Notes (Folder 2)
        - Reports. Includes financial expenditures (Folder 3)
        - Telegrams (Folder 4)
  - 1945
    - General (Folder 5)
    - Office file
      - General (Folder 6-7)
      - Articles and other printed matter (Folder 8)
      - Memoranda (Folder 9)
      - Memoranda (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
      - Reports (Folder 3-5)
      - Statements (Folder 6)
    - Subject file
      - Belgium (Folder 7)
      - Denmark (Folder 8)
      - Finland
        - General (Box 13, Folder 1)
        - Department of State
          - Airgram (Folder 2)
          - Press release (Folder 3)
          - Telegram (Folder 4)
        - Articles and other printed matter (Folder 5)
        - Cables and dispatches (Folder 6)
        - Memoranda (Folder 7)
        - Notes (Folder 8)
        - Reports (Folder 9)
      - France (Folder 10)
      - Germany (Folder 11)
      - Netherlands (Folder 12)
      - Norway
        - General (Folder 13)
        - Cables and dispatches (Folder 14)
        - Department of State
          - Press releases (Folder 15)
          - Telegram (Folder 16)
        - Memoranda (Folder 17)
        - Notes (Folder 18)
        - Politics and government (Folder 19)
        - Reports (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
      - Poland (Folder 3)
      - Propaganda flyers (American). In German and English (Folder 4)
      - Scandinavia (Folder 5)
      - Sweden
        - General. Includes introduction to the history of the OWI (Folder 6)
        - Articles and other printed matter (Folder 7-8)
        - Memoranda (Folder 9)
        - Notes (Folder 10)
        - Reports (Folder 11)
      - United States Information Service (USIS). Includes Paris Press-Radio Comments (Folder 12-13)
      - Voice of America (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Yale Institute of International Studies (Folder 2)
- INTERIM INTERNATIONAL INFORMATION DIVISION (IIID), 1945 SEPTEMBER 16-DECEMBER 31
  - General (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Office files
    - General (Folder 4)
    - Memoranda (Folder 5)
    - Personnel lists (Folder 6)
    - Press releases (Folder 7)
    - Recommendations (Folder 8)
  - Subject file
    - China (Folder 9)
    - Denmark (Folder 10)
    - Finland (Folder 11)
    - Germany (Folder 12)
    - Italy (Folder 13)
    - Norway (Folder 14)
    - Propaganda (American) (Folder 15)
    - Southeast Asia (Folder 16)
    - Soviet Union (Folder 17)
    - Sweden (Folder 18)
    - United States Information Service. Includes monthly reports (Folder 19)
    - Voice of America (Box 16, Folder 1)
- OFFICE OF INTERNATIONAL INFORMATION AND CULTURAL AFFAIRS (OIC), 1946 JANUARY-AUGUST AND 1949 AUGUST
  (As of 1947 August this office merged with the Office of Information and Educational Exchange -up until this time both had existed separately in the Department of State under the Public Affairs Assistant Secretary)
  - General (undated)
    - General (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Belgium (Folder 3)
    - Harriman, W. Averell (Folder 4)
    - Soviet Union (Folder 5)
    - Sweden (Folder 6)
    - United States Information Service (Folder 7)
  - Office files (undated)
    - Budget (Folder 8)
    - Correspondence (Folder 9)
    - Daily log (Folder 10)
    - Memoranda (Folder 11)
    - Newsletters (Folder 12)
    - Notes (Folder 13)
    - Personnel list (Folder 14)
    - Press releases (Folder 15)
    - Procedures and operations (Folder 16)
    - Reports (Folder 17)
  - 1945 (Folder 18)
  - 1946
    - General (Folder 19)
    - Department of State
      - General (Folder 20)
      - Office of Public Affairs (Folder 21)
      - Press releases (Folder 22)
      - Printed matter (Folder 23)
      - Telegrams (Folder 24)
    - Division of International Press and Publications (INP) (Folder 25)
    - International Broadcasting Division (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Office files
      - Budget (Folder 2)
      - Correspondence (Folder 3)
      - Memoranda (Folder 4-5)
      - Personnel lists (Folder 6)
      - Procedures and operations (Folder 7-9)
      - Reports (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
    - Subject file
      - Albania (Folder 3)
      - Australia (Folder 4)
      - Belgium (Folder 5)
      - Britain (Folder 6)
      - China (Folder 7)
      - Czechoslovakia (Folder 8-9)
      - Denmark (Folder 10)
      - Finland
        - Department of State-telegrams (Box 19, Folder 1)
        - Memoranda (Folder 2)
        - Reports (Folder 3)
      - France (Folder 4)
      - Germany (Folder 5)
      - Greece (Folder 6)
      - Hungary (Folder 7)
      - Iceland (Folder 8)
      - India (Folder 9)
      - Italy (Folder 10-11)
      - Netherlands (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - New Zealand (Folder 2)
      - Norway (Folder 3)
      - Poland (Folder 4)
      - Portugal (Folder 5)
      - Rumania (Folder 6)
      - South Africa (Folder 7)
      - Soviet Union (Folder 8)
      - Spain (Folder 9)
      - Sweden (Folder 10)
      - Switzerland (Folder 11)
      - Yugoslavia (Folder 12)
    - United States Information Service (USIS)
      - General (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Australia (Folder 2)
      - Britain (Folder 3)
      - Denmark (Folder 4)
      - Finland (Folder 5)
      - Italy (Folder 6)
      - Sweden (Folder 7-9)
    - United States Information Service (USIS)-Office of International Information and Cultural Affairs (OIC)
      - Britain (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Bulgaria (Folder 2)
      - Denmark (Folder 3)
      - Netherlands (Folder 4)
      - Norway (Folder 5)
      - Portugal (Folder 6)
      - Switzerland (Folder 7)
  - 1947
    - Department of State
      - Division of Libraries and Institutes (Folder 8)
      - Office of Public Affairs (Folder 9)
      - Press releases (Folder 10)
      - Printed matter (Folder 11)
      - Telegrams (Folder 12)
    - Division of International Press and Publications (Folder 13-14)
    - Division of International Press and Publications (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - International Broadcasting Division (Folder 2)
    - Office files
      - General (Folder 3)
      - Budget (Folder 4)
      - Correspondence (Folder 5)
      - Memoranda (Folder 6)
      - Reports (Folder 7)
    - Subject file
      - Algeria (Folder 8)
      - Australia (Folder 9)
      - Belgium (Folder 10)
      - Britain (Folder 11)
      - Czechoslovakia (Folder 12)
      - Denmark (Folder 13)
      - Europe (Folder 14)
      - Far East (Folder 15)
      - Finland (Folder 16)
      - Fulbright Act and awards (Folder 17)
      - Hungary (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Italy (Folder 2)
      - Latin America (Folder 3)
      - Middle East and Africa (Folder 4)
      - New Zealand (Folder 5)
      - Norway (Folder 6)
      - Poland (Folder 7)
      - Portugal (Folder 8)
      - South Africa (Folder 9)
      - Soviet Union (Folder 10)
      - Sweden (Folder 11)
      - Yugoslavia (Folder 12)
    - United States Information Service (USIS)
      - General (Folder 13)
      - Reports (Folder 14)
      - Subject file
        - Iceland (Folder 15)
        - Italy (Folder 16)
        - France (Folder 17)
        - Libraries (Folder 18)
        - Sweden (Folder 19)
    - United States Information Service (USIS)-Office of International Information and Cultural Activities (OIC)
      - Britain (Folder 20)
      - Czechoslovakia (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Denmark (Folder 2)
      - France (Folder 3-5)
      - Greece (Folder 6)
      - Italy (Folder 7)
      - Norway (Folder 8)
      - Poland (Folder 9)
      - Portugal (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - United States Information Service (USIS)-Office of Information and Educational Exchange (OIE)
      - Denmark (Folder 2)
      - Finland (Folder 3)
      - Netherlands (Folder 4)
      - Norway (Folder 5)
    - Voice of America (Folder 6)
  - 1948
    - General (Folder 7)
    - Department of State - Press releases (Folder 8)
    - Division of International Press and Publications (Folder 9)
    - Finland (Folder 10)
    - Office files - Budget (Folder 11-13)
    - United States Information Service (USIS)
      - Britain (Folder 14)
      - Iceland (Folder 15)
      - Sweden (Folder 16)
    - United States Information Service (USIS)-Office of Information and Educational Exchange (OIE)
      - Denmark (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - Finland (Folder 2)
      - Norway (Folder 3)
- PUBLIC AFFAIRS OFFICER, 1949-1951 AUGUST
  - General
    - General (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Propaganda
      - Britain (Folder 5)
      - Ceylon (Folder 6)
      - China (Folder 7)
      - Italy (Folder 8)
      - Korea (Folder 9)
      - Latin America (Folder 10)
      - Netherlands (Folder 11)
      - Norway (Folder 12)
      - Poland (Folder 13)
      - Soviet Union (Folder 14-15)
      - Sweden (Box 28, Folder 1-4)
      - United States (Folder 5-6)
      - United States (Box 29, Folder 1-2)
      - Yugoslavia (Folder 3)
  - International Broadcasting Division (Folder 4-5)
  - United States Information and International Educational Exchange Program (USIE)
    - General (Folder 6)
    - Printed matter (Folder 7)
    - Reports
      - 1949 (Folder 8)
      - 1950 (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - 1951-1953 (Folder 2)
  - United States Information Service
    - Printed matter
      - General (Folder 3)
      - Air Bulletin (Folder 4)
      - News Digest (Folder 5)
      - U.S.A. News Review (Folder 6)
      - Via Air Mail (Folder 7)
    - Subject file
      - General (Folder 8)
      - Belgium (Folder 9)
      - Denmark (Folder 10)
      - Finland (Folder 11)
      - Germany (Folder 12)
      - Italy (Folder 13)
      - Norway (Folder 14)
      - Sweden (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - Voice of America (Folder 2)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1928-1979
  - America First Committee (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - American Liberty League (Folder 4-6)
  - American-Scandinavian Committee (Folder 7)
  - American Student Union (Folder 8)
  - American Universities Field Staff (Folder 9)
  - Association Against the Prohibition Amendment (Folder 10)
  - Association Against the Prohibition Amendment (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Australia (Folder 2)
  - Austria (Folder 3)
  - Belgium
    - Cables and dispatches (Folder 4)
    - Department of State - telegrams (Folder 5)
    - Politics and government (Folder 6)
  - Britain
    - General (Folder 7)
    - Articles (Folder 8)
    - Notes (Folder 9)
    - Politics and government (Folder 10)
    - Printed matter
      - General (Folder 11)
      - Government (Folder 12)
    - Reports (Folder 13)
  - California Crusaders (Folder 14)
  - Canada (Folder 15)
  - Civil rights (Folder 16)
  - Committee for the Defense of the Consitution (Folder 17)
  - Committee for Free Asia (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Committee on Foreign Policy Legislation (Folder 2)
  - Committee on Pan American Policy (Folder 3)
  - Communism (Folder 4)
  - Council for Democracy (Folder 5)
  - Cuba (Folder 6)
  - Denmark
    - General (Folder 7)
    - American Friends of Danish Freedom and Democracy (Folder 8)
    - Articles (Folder 9)
    - Cables and dispatches (Folder 10)
    - Danish Information Service
      - Economic and Commercial Conditions in Denmark (Folder 11)
      - Monthly Economic Report
        - 1951-1953 (Folder 12)
        - 1954-1955 (Folder 13)
    - Free Denmark (Folder 14)
    - National America Denmark Association (Folder 15)
    - Notes (Folder 16)
    - Politics and government (Folder 17)
    - Printed matter (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Speeches and statements
      - General (Folder 2)
      - Government officials (Folder 3)
  - Department of State
    - Foreign Service
      - General (Folder 4)
      - Exam (Folder 5)
      - Foreign Service Act, 1946 (Folder 6)
      - Memoranda (Folder 7)
      - Printed matter (Folder 8)
      - Recruitment and training (Folder 9)
      - Reports (Folder 10)
      - Reports (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - Speeches and statements by department officials (Folder 2)
    - Office file
      - General (Folder 3-5)
      - Budget (Folder 6)
      - Departmental announcements (Folder 7)
      - Memoranda (Folder 8)
      - Notes (Folder 9)
      - Personnel (Folder 10)
      - Press releases
        - 1944-1946 (Folder 11)
        - 1947 (Box 36, Folder 1)
        - 1948 (Folder 2-4)
        - 1948-1950 (Folder 5)
        - 1951-1952 (Folder 6)
        - 1953 (Folder 7)
        - 1954 (Box 37, Folder 1)
        - 1955 (Folder 2)
        - 1956-1962 (Folder 3)
        - 1963 (Folder 4)
        - 1964-1965 (Folder 5)
      - Printed matter
        - General (Folder 6-7)
        - General (Box 38, Folder 1-6)
        - General (Box 39, Folder 1-2)
        - Bulletin (Folder 3)
        - The Record (Folder 4)
        - Wireless Bulletin (Folder 5)
      - Reports (Folder 6-8)
      - Speeches and statement of department official (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Estonia (Folder 2)
  - Europe
    - General (Folder 3)
    - Eastern (Folder 4)
  - Finland
    - General (Folder 5)
    - Articles (Folder 6)
    - Cables and dispatches (Folder 7)
    - Finnish American Chamber of Commerce (Folder 8)
    - Legation of Finland (Folder 9)
    - Memoranda (Folder 10)
    - Notes (Folder 11)
    - Politics and government
      - General (Folder 12)
      - Ministry for Foreign Affairs
        - Finnish Features
          - 1962 (Folder 13)
          - 1963 (Folder 14)
        - Reports (Folder 15)
    - Printed matter (Folder 16)
    - Reports (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Speeches and statements
      - General (Folder 2)
      - Government officials (Folder 3)
  - France (Folder 4)
  - Germany
    - General (Folder 5)
    - Articles (Folder 6)